Cody Webb

Columbus, OH 43214, USA

Phone: 614-549-0355 | Email: webbcody36@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cody-webb-6041a718b/ | GitHub: https://github.com/cody3629 | Portfolio: https://cody3629.github.io/Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer coming from a five year background in Finance - with a passion for integrating technologies to solve problems, create user-friendly applications, and improve upon existing methods. Effective at writing testable, efficient code using current best practices in Web Development. Strengths in problem-solving, creativity, and building projects from ideation to execution.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, MySQL, React.js, JSX, GitHub, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, REST APIs, AJAX, JSON.

Experience

Abercrombie & Fitch | Web Content Developer | June 2022 - Present

Summary: Develop content passed from marketing and design partners using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Build content for domestic and international sites/apps. Develop complex content for seasonal pieces. Use project management tools to execute the content schedule to build seasonal and daily content on time. Experienced in using JIRA and HCL Commerce to manage and schedule content. Partner with marketing, design, and strategy to align on content execution. Complete development quickly and accurately in a fast-paced environment to meet deadlines. Manage multiple projects at once and shift priorities when needed. Debug and test code/content for quality assurance.

Huntington National Bank | Mortgage Processor | July 2021 - Oct 2021

Summary: Executed underwriting tasks on mortgage loan applications, and collaborated with the mortgage and underwriting teams to process loans. Examined and verified information in loan application and closing documents. Submitted completed loan applications, including recommendations for underwriting approval or denial. Worked with third-party vendors to address and clear loan closing requirements. Checked applicant credit, personal references and employment histories. Prepared and delivered loan documents to title and escrow teams. Assembled and compiled title abstracts, insurance forms, loan documents and tax receipts.

Smartbiz | Underwriter | Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Summary: Performed underwriting on PPP applications for small businesses. Assisted clients with application issues. Detected and analyzed fraudulent activity on PPP applications. Analyzed applications to make sure they met SBA and PPP requirements. Evaluated tax forms for accuracy. Handled a daily pipeline of 150-200 applications per day. Communicate with team members and clients on changing guidelines through email and meetings. Resolved client inquiries. Reached daily and weekly underwriting goals for processing applications.

Fifth Third Bank | Personal Banker | Jul 2017 - Oct 2020

Summary: Assisted clients daily in opening and closing accounts/loans, and cross-sell related solutions. Exceeded sales goals. Advised banking services and solutions to clients based on their financial needs. Managed clients day to day queries related to their personal accounts. Presented and sold banking services and products to existing and prospective clients. Prepared documentation to open or close accounts/loans, including obtaining signatures, and assigning account numbers, when necessary. Processed applications for credit cards, loans, and mortgages.

Development Projects

MGC Fitness | Back End Developer | gitub.com/cody3629/gym-management

Summary: Web Application for a local gym that has an interactive and attractive UI, user login, and data for customers and employees including customer profile and trainer plans.

Tools: JavaScript, Express, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB, Sequelize, HTML5, CSS3.

Note Taker | Lead Developer | github.com/cody3629/note.taker | https://agile-forest-32357.herokuapp.com

Summary: Web Application that allows a user to write, save, and delete notes using Express for the purpose of keeping track of information.

Tools: Express.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js.

Tech Blog | Lead Developer | github.com/cody3629/tech-blog | https://powerful-forest-60459.herokuapp.com

Summary: Web Application for posting tech related blogs that also allows a user to create an account, post blogs, comment on blogs, and delete created blogs on their account.

Tools: Express, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Node.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize

Employee Manager | Lead Developer | https://github.com/cody3629/Employee-Manager

Summary: Interface Application for managing a company's employees. You could view, add, remove, and update employees.

Tools: JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL

Team Profile Generator | Lead Developer | https://github.com/cody3629/Team-Profile-Generator

Summary: Interface Application for creating and inputting information for a software team, then the inputted info would be displayed on a webpage.

Tools: Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Jest

READme Generator | Lead Developer | https://github.com/cody3629/READme-Generator

Summary: Interface Application that will generate a README.md file based on user inputted information from the terminal.

Tools: Node.js, JavaScript

E-Commerce Backend | Lead Developer | https://github.com/cody3629/E-Commerce-Backend

Summary: Backend for an e-commerce website to give the website working functionality and a competitive edge.

Tools: Node.js, JavaScript, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize

Education

The Ohio State University | Full-Stack Web Development Certificate | Oct. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Columbus State Community College | Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2017

Youngstown State University | Aug. 2015 - May 2016